<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hands-on sessions on</title><link>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/</link><description>Recent content in Hands-on sessions on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenFOAM environment 101</title><link>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/openfoam-env-101/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/openfoam-env-101/</guid><description>You need to be on a Linux machine somehow.
Common options if you&amp;rsquo;re running on a Linux OS (or macOS, choose what suits you):
OpenFOAM in a Docker container (Preferred method). A local installation of OpenFOAM. Github&amp;rsquo;s Codespace for a fully remote experience (which uses the same Docker image and the unit testing framework). If your main OS is Windows, you have a couple of options (Again, choose whatever you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with):</description></item><item><title>OpenFOAM in containers</title><link>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/openfoam-in-containers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/openfoam-in-containers/</guid><description>There are many OpenFOAM images for all sorts of containerization systems out there. However, my images, which are hosted at ghcr.io, are specifically built to participate in MPI communications:
ghcr.io/foamscience/jammy-openfoam:v2206 ghcr.io/foamscience/jammy-openfoam:fe5 ghcr.io/foamscience/jammy-openfoam:9 You can fire up a quick local container with the following Shell command (Assuming Docker is installed - see get.docker.com):
docker run \ --rm `# Disposable container, destroyed as soon as you leave it.` \ -it `# Interactive with a tty so you can run a shell` \ --name openfoam `# Container name` \ ghcr.</description></item><item><title>A unit-testing framework to do the exercises</title><link>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/using-foamut/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/using-foamut/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll be using the unit-testing framework as a black-box to verify the correctness of your code in hands-on sessions. You only need to change one file per activity; Mostly Exercises are provided as test units for convenient interaction with the code (compile-run-debug cycles). Clone this repo and run Alltest using your local OpenFOAM installation to make sure everything works as expected. The following diagram depicts the general workflow of solving the exercises proposed during the hands-on sessions:</description></item><item><title>Github classroom for the exercises</title><link>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/github-classroom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/github-classroom/</guid><description>All activities during the workshop&amp;rsquo;s hands-on sessions will be prepared as assignments. This page holds the complete list of offered activities/exercises.
👉 Each assignment will create a separate private repository for you at this Github organisation First, let&amp;rsquo;s start by the introductory ones:
Accept assignment Optional Git &amp;amp; Github Fundamentals A basic fast-paced course to get you familiarized with Git and Github in general - Provided by Github Classrooms. Please go through the README.</description></item><item><title>Run tests on a SLURM cluster</title><link>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/run-on-the-slurm-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://openfoam-parallelisation-course.github.io/workshop/hands-on/run-on-the-slurm-cluster/</guid><description>👉 Please attempt to do this only after you feel comfortable enough with running the unit tests using Alltest script. Now that you&amp;rsquo;re feeling more confident about reading/writing MPI-ready code in OpenFOAM; it&amp;rsquo;s time we put what you learned so far to work. In this activity, you&amp;rsquo;ll try to run your unit-tests from previous exercises in a SLURM cluster (which emulated real-world clusters, but is made up from Docker containers instead of physical machines for convenience).</description></item></channel></rss>